nextdirect.com 2012-05-02

# Next International

UNITED STATES OF AMERICA PRIVACY POLICY

Scope   
This Security & Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies to the web site (nextdirect.com) (the “Site”), which is operated by or on behalf of Next Retail Ltd. a UK company (“we”, “us” or “Next”). This Policy applies only to information collected through the Site and does not apply to information collected from any other source. 

Security   
Next takes online security very seriously and is a registered licensee of the VeriSign Secured® Seal under VeriSign’s SSL Certificate Authority.  
How Do We Protect Your Information?

We use a server certificate (also known as a digital certificate) to enhance your confidence in our identity when you log in or conduct a transaction and we use secure sockets layer (SSL) technology to protect data transmissions.

If you want to check our certificate/security you can do so using one of the following methods:

From your browser when you are within the Site:  
Microsoft Internet Explorer 4 or later  
Click on the gold padlock at the bottom right of your browser to bring up the details of this Site's Digital ID.

Mozilla Firefox  
Click on the yellow padlock at the bottom left of your browser to bring up the security information.

Opera  
Click on the padlock within the address bar of your browser to bring up the security information.

At the Verisign web site  
The VeriSign web site enables you to validate the security of our pages online. Validate our secure server. Alternatively, click on the VeriSign Secured® Seal throughout secure areas of nextdirect.com.

The security measures described above are just some of the administrative, technical, and physical steps we take to protect your personal information. However, the open nature of the Internet means that an absolute guarantee of security cannot be offered, and you should be aware that even with all the measures we take, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information.

Privacy

As a UK company, subject to strict European privacy rules, Next is committed to complying with the privacy requirements of the UK Data Protection Act 1998. Even though you may not be in Europe, our computer servers are in the UK and so your personal information is protected in accordance with UK privacy laws. Because this Site is directed toward North American customers, we also respect those privacy rules to the extent they are more protective than UK privacy law. The purpose of this Policy is to help you understand how and why Next collects information from you, to whom such information is disclosed and what your rights are. You can access our Site and browse our site without disclosing your personal data. However, when you register with Next you will be asked to provide certain information about yourself.

What Information Do We Collect And How Do We Obtain It?

When you visit our Site, we collect information that in the US is not considered personally identifiable information. For example, in order to monitor and improve the Site we may gather certain information including details of your domain name and IP address, operating system, browser, version and the website that you visited prior to this Site. This may involve the use of a cookie that will not expire at the end of your browsing session. (Our use of cookies is described in detail below.)

We receive information in one of two ways either directly from you when you register with us or from a third party such as credit reference agencies (for example to assess your credit rating).

When you create an account on the Site or make a purchase from the Site, we collect information so that we can identify you and respond to your requests. If you register with us you will be asked to provide certain information such as your name, address, details of your credit card (only if you are paying by credit card), telephone number and email address so that we can process and fulfill your order, notify you of your order status and inform you of special offers and promotions.

How Do We Use Your Information?

We use the information that we collect about you to: 

  1. Process your orders
  2. Manage your account - see also "Use of credit reference agency information".
  3. Administer this website.
  4. Monitor customer traffic patterns and Site usage to help us develop and improve the design and layout of the Site.
  5. Notify you about enhancement to our services, such as changes to the website, new services and special offers that may be of interest.

If you have given us permission to send you information about our products and services by telephone, email or in writing, Next will do so in accordance with the US CAN-SPAM Act, state and federal telemarketing laws, as well as the UK Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003 and the Direct Marketing Association (DMA) Code of Practice. 

Use of Consumer Reporting Agency Information and sharing of credit information   
We may share information about you and the conduct of your account with consumer reporting agencies, other lenders and relevant third parties, in accordance with applicable law.  
Information about you and other members of your household and those with whom you are financially linked maybe used to verify your identity.   
We may also use your information for payment recovery or fraud and debt tracing. We will pass on details of defaulting accounts to debt collection agencies.  
For details of the Credit Reference Agencies that we receive information from and share information with, please feel free to inquire via any of the means available in the Contact Us section below. 

Who Does Next Disclose The Information It Collects To?   
We use information about you for purposes other than the provision of a website shopping facility. As a result we may disclose your information to: 

  1. Credit Reference Agencies - for more information see above.
  2. Legal and debt recovery representatives for debt collection and debtor tracing purposes.
  3. Reputable companies to fulfill your order or process your data on our behalf.
  4. We may disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order, law enforcement agency’s request, or as otherwise required by law. Additionally, your personally identifiable information may be disclosed and/or transferred to a third-party if we file for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of Next in connection with proposed or consummated corporate reorganizations, such as a merger or acquisition.

Next Directory is a trading name of Next Retail Limited and a member of Next Group plc.  
We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize our services, content and advertising.  
This may also be done on a reciprocal basis. From time to time, we make portions of our customer list available to carefully screened companies. If you do not want your name and mailing details made available, or no longer choose to receive a Next catalog or wish to alert us to duplicate mailings, please call us on our helpline number or email marketing@next.com. Next is committed to respecting your privacy. 

Keeping in Touch with You   

We want to keep you up to date with information about new ranges, special offers and improvements to this site. When you provide us your email address, we may send you emails necessary to process your order, respond to a request, provide customer service, or promote products or services. For example, after you place an order at www.nextdirect.com, you will receive an email confirmation and, in most cases, an email with package tracking information.

It is our intent to send promotional emails only to those persons who wish to receive them. We provide instructions on how to unsubscribe in each marketing email message and each edition of the newsletter and within the "Updating and Reviewing Your Information" below.

Alternatively, you can request that we stop using your information and that we stop mailing information to you by calling us toll-free at 1-(888)-385-6398, by email at privacy@nextdirect.com, or by writing to the Group Data Protection Manager at our headquarters indicated in the Contact Us section below.

You may continue to receive mailings that are already on route to you for a short period of time while your request is being dealt with.

What About Cookies?   
Our online ordering system uses a cookie to record a unique reference on your computer so that we can keep track of your order as you use the Site. A cookie is a small data file that is stored by your web browser on your computer. Cookies enable you to place an order on our Site. They also allow us to enhance and personalize your online shopping experience, so that the information we receive is more relevant to you. For example, we use cookies to: 

  1. Remember what items are in your Shopping Bag.
  2. Recognize you when you return to our site.
  3. Enable you to use Express Checkout, if you have created an account on the site.
  4. Study how our customers navigate through our Site and which products they request in Site searches

This cookie, that is saved to your system, is only valid for a single visit and each new visit will result in a new cookie overwriting any previous that were generated on previous visits to our site. If your internet browser is set to reject cookies or if your network firewall won't allow them then unfortunately you will not be able to use our online store. If you set your browser to refuse cookies, please call us toll-free at 1-(888)-385-6398 to place your order. Please refer to your internet browser help file to see how to enable cookies on your p.c. 

Links to Other Sites   
Occasionally we provide links on our Site to other sites we think you will enjoy. Next is not responsible for the content on any of these sites. These sites operate independently of Next and have established their own privacy and security policies. For the best online experience, we strongly encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit. 

Updating or Reviewing Your Information   
To update your customer information, such as name, address, telephone number, email address or billing details, please log in to any profile you have created and make the modifications directly within the Site. A limited amount of purchase information may also be available to you. To protect your privacy, we will need to validate your identity before you update or review your information. If you do this via the Site, we will ask you for your user name and password. You may also contact us toll-free at 1-(888)-385-6398 or via postal mail at the address in the Contact Us section below. 

Account Protection   
Your password is the key to your account. Use unique numbers, letters and special characters, and do not disclose your password to anyone. If you do share your password or your personal information with others, remember that you are responsible for all actions taken in the name of your account. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately notify us and change your password. 

The Direct Marketing Association   
Next is a member of the Direct Marketing Association (DMA) and is required to operate within the rules of the DMA Code of Practice. This means that Next operates to a high level of commercial standards that are designed to: 

  1. Protect your privacy.
  2. Ensure that payments are secure.
  3. Let you know what you have agreed to.
  4. Sort out any complaints.

For more information on the DMA, visit www.dma.org.uk 

We hope to answer any questions about this Policy to your satisfaction, and so if you ever have any questions or complaints about how we handle your personal information please contact us first so that we can assist you. If you are not satisfied with our response regarding our privacy practices, you can email the Direct Marketing Association's Committee on Ethical Business Practices at ethics@the-dma.org. The DMA is the oldest and largest association for consumers and companies with interest in direct marketing.

Monitoring Communications   
As part of our efforts to make further improvements to the service we provide to our customers, telephone calls to and from Next may be recorded or monitored and used for training purposes. To protect the operation of our computer systems we monitor incoming and outgoing email. 

Privacy of Children on our Site   
Our Site is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. 

Changes to the Privacy Policy   
We keep our Policy under regular review and we will place any updates on the Site along with a summary of any material changes. 

Contact Us   
If you have any questions relating to this policy or the use by Next of personal data please contact us via:  
Toll-free: 1-(888)-385-6398  
Email: privacy@nextdirect.com  
Post: Group Data Protection Manager  
Next Retail Ltd.  
Desford Road,  
Enderby,  
Leicester.  
UK  
LE19 4AT  
This Policy was last updated on December 8th, 2011.
